and gone out of our way to try to find the very best people we can, mostly fail to get the best out of them. So how do we develop the skills that we need? Because it does take skill and practice, too. If we aren't going to be afraid of conflict, we have to see it as thinking, and then we have to get really good at it. So, recently, I worked with an executive named Joe, and Joe worked for a medical device company. And Joe was very worried about the device that he was working on. He thought that it was too complicated and he thought that its complexity created margins of error that could really hurt people. He was afraid of doing damage to the patients he was trying to help. But when he looked around his organization, nobody else seemed to be at all worried. So, he didn't really want to say anything. After all, maybe they knew something he didn't. Maybe he'd look stupid. But he kept worrying about it, and he worried about it so much that he got to the point where he thought the only thing he could do was leave a job he loved. In the end, Joe and I found a way for him to raise his concerns. And what happened then is what almost always happens in this situation. It turned out everybody had exactly the same questions and doubts. So now Joe had allies. They could think together. And yes, there was a lot of conflict and debate and argument, but that allowed everyone around the table to be creative, to solve the problem, and to change the device. Joe was what a lot of people might think of as a whistle-blower, except that like almost all whistle-blowers, he wasn't a crank at all, he was passionately devoted to the organization and the higher purposes that that organization served. But he had been so afraid of conflict, until finally he became more afraid of the silence. And when he dared to speak, he discovered much more inside himself and much more give in the system than he had ever imagined. And his colleagues don't think of him as a crank. They think of him as a leader. So, how do we have these conversations more easily and more often? Well, the University of Delft requires that its PhD students have to submit five statements that they're prepared to defend. It doesn't really matter what the statements are about, what matters is that the candidates are willing and able to stand up to authority. I think it's a fantastic system, but I think leaving it to PhD candidates is far too few people, and way too late in life. I think we need to be teaching these skills to kids and adults at every stage of their development, if we want to have thinking organizations and a thinking society. The fact is that most of the biggest catastrophes that we've witnessed rarely come from information that is secret or hidden. It comes from information that is freely available and out there, but that we are willfully blind to, because we can't handle, don't want to handle, the conflict that it provokes. But when we dare to break that silence, or when we dare to see, and we create conflict, we enable ourselves and the people around us to do our very best thinking. Open information is fantastic, open networks are essential. But the truth won't set us free until we develop the skills and the habit and the talent and the moral courage to use it. Openness isn't the end. It's the beginning. (Applause)
y hemos intentado encontrar a las mejores personas posibles, mayormente fallamos en lograr lo mejor de ellas. ¿Cómo desarrollamos las habilidades que necesitamos? Porque hace falta habilidad y práctica, también. Si no vamos a tenerle miedo al conflicto, tenemos que verlo como una forma de pensar y luego tenemos que conseguir ser realmente buenos en ello. Recientemente, trabajé con un ejecutivo llamado Joe, que trabajaba para una compañía de equipos médicos. Joe estaba muy preocupado por el equipo en que estaba trabajando. Pensaba que era demasiado complicado y que su complejidad generaba márgenes de error que realmente podrían lastimar personas. Tenía miedo de hacer daño a los pacientes que intentaba ayudar. Pero cuando miró alrededor de su organización, nadie parecía preocuparse en absoluto. Así que él realmente no quería decir nada. Después de todo, tal vez sabían algo que él no sabía. Tal vez parecería un tonto. Pero seguía preocupado y tanto, que llegó hasta el punto en que pensó que lo único que podía hacer era renunciar al trabajo que amaba. Al final, Joe y yo encontramos una manera para que planteara sus inquietudes. Y lo que sucedió entonces es lo que casi siempre sucede en esta situación. Resultó que todo el mundo tenía exactamente las mismas preguntas y dudas. Así que ahora Joe tenía aliados. Podrían pensar juntos. Y sí, hubo mucho debate y conflicto y discusiones, pero esto permitió que todos alrededor de la mesa fueran creativos, solucionaran problemas, y que modificaran el equipo. Mucha gente pensaría que Joe era una especie de soplón, excepto que, a diferencia de casi todos los soplones, él no era para nada un oportunista, era un devoto apasionado de su empresa y de los propósitos superiores que ésta buscaba. Pero había tenido mucho miedo al conflicto, hasta que finalmente fue mayor su miedo al silencio. Y cuando se atrevió a hablar, descubrió mucho más dentro de sí mismo para aportar al sistema, de lo que él nunca había imaginado. Y sus colegas no creen que sea un oportunista. Lo ven como líder. Así que, ¿cómo podemos tener estas conversaciones más fácilmente y más a menudo? Bueno, la Universidad de Delft exige que los estudiantes de doctorado tengan que presentar cinco informes que estén preparados para defender. Realmente no importa el contenido de los informes, lo que importa es que los candidatos estén dispuestos y sean capaces de enfrentar a la autoridad. Creo que es un sistema fantástico, pero creo que dejarlo para candidatos a doctorado es para muy pocas personas y muy tarde en la vida. Creo que tenemos que enseñar estas habilidades a niños y adultos en cada etapa de su desarrollo, si queremos tener organizaciones que piensen y una sociedad pensante. El hecho es que la mayoría de las grandes catástrofes de las que hemos sido testigos, rara vez vienen de información que es secreta u oculta. Vienen de información que está disponible libremente pero a la que somos intencionalmente ciegos, porque no podemos o no queremos afrontar el conflicto que esto provoca. Pero cuando nos atrevemos a romper ese silencio, o cuando nos atrevemos a ver, y creamos el conflicto, nos habilitamos a nosotros y quienes nos rodean para nuestro mejor pensamiento. La información abierta es fantástica, las redes abiertas son esenciales. Pero la verdad no nos liberará hasta que desarrollemos las habilidades, el hábito, el talento y el coraje moral para utilizarla. La apertura no es el fin. Es el comienzo. (Aplausos)